[
  
    {
      "question": "281. Which of these is especially true about your tires in hot weather?",
      "choices": [
        "You should check tire mounting and air pressure before driving.",
        "If a tire is too hot to touch, you should hose it down with water.",
        "A small amount of air should be let out to keep air pressure steady."
      ],
      "answer": "You should check tire mounting and air pressure before driving."
    },
    {
      "question": "282. When driving through roadway work zones, you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Reduce speed only if workers are close to the roadway.",
        "Turn on your parking lights.",
        "Watch for sharp pavement drop-offs."
      ],
      "answer": "Watch for sharp pavement drop-offs."
    },
    {
      "question": "283. Which of these statements is true about bad weather driving conditions?",
      "choices": [
        "When the temperature drops, bridges will freeze before roadways.",
        "The road becomes more slippery as rain continues than when the rain began.",
        "Driving conditions become more dangerous as the temperature rises."
      ],
      "answer": "When the temperature drops, bridges will freeze before roadways."
    },
    {
      "question": "284. Which of these statements is true about other drivers?",
      "choices": [
        "Mail or delivery truck drivers do not pose a hazard.",
        "Drivers using turn signals can be trusted to turn in the direction they indicate.",
        "Short-term or daily rental truck drivers are often not used to the limited vision and pose a hazard."
      ],
      "answer": "Short-term or daily rental truck drivers are often not used to the limited vision and pose a hazard."
    },
    {
      "question": "285. Which of these will happen if a tire blows out at highway speeds?",
      "choices": [
        "A rapid drop in speed to below 20 mph.",
        "A loud hissing sound.",
        "A vibrating feeling."
      ],
      "answer": "A vibrating feeling."
    },
    {
      "question": "286. To prevent 'brake fade' you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Select a gear that will keep your vehicle to a safe speed on steep downgrades.",
        "Apply constant hard pressure on the brakes.",
        "Coast down hills that are not very steep inclines."
      ],
      "answer": "Select a gear that will keep your vehicle to a safe speed on steep downgrades."
    },
    {
      "question": "287. If you have been drinking alcohol, before you drive, you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Take a cold shower.",
        "Wait for it to wear off.",
        "Drink coffee."
      ],
      "answer": "Wait for it to wear off."
    },
    {
      "question": "288. Which of the following best describes how sleep debt can be paid off?",
      "choices": [
        "Overcome it with willpower and non-sleep aids.",
        "It will go away by itself over a period of time.",
        "It can only be paid off by sleeping."
      ],
      "answer": "It can only be paid off by sleeping."
    },
    {
      "question": "289. Which of these statements is true about drugs?",
      "choices": [
        "The use of alcohol or drugs can lead to collision and/or arrest.",
        "A driver can use any prescription drug while driving.",
        "Certain prescription drugs are allowed to reduce fatigue."
      ],
      "answer": "The use of alcohol or drugs can lead to collision and/or arrest."
    },
    {
      "question": "290. 'Implied consent' means when you sign the driver's license application form, you:",
      "choices": [
        "Understand that you may drink alcohol now before driving.",
        "Give your consent to be tested for alcohol in your blood.",
        "Give your consent for your vehicle to be inspected for alcohol."
      ],
      "answer": "Give your consent to be tested for alcohol in your blood."
    },
    {
      "question": "291. You should use your mirrors to check:",
      "choices": [
        "Your blind spots only.",
        "If your running lights are working properly.",
        "Where the rear of your vehicle is while you make turns."
      ],
      "answer": "Where the rear of your vehicle is while you make turns."
    },
    {
      "question": "292. Convex curved mirrors:",
      "choices": [
        "Make objects appear larger than they really are.",
        "Make objects appear closer than they really are.",
        "Show a wider area than flat mirrors."
      ],
      "answer": "Show a wider area than flat mirrors."
    },
    {
      "question": "293. The purpose of retarders is to:",
      "choices": [
        "Help slow the vehicle while driving and reduce brake wear.",
        "Apply extra braking power to the non-drive axles.",
        "Help prevent skids and reduce brake wear."
      ],
      "answer": "Help slow the vehicle while driving and reduce brake wear."
    },
    {
      "question": "294. It is important to shift gears correctly to keep:",
      "choices": [
        "Control of the vehicle.",
        "The engine warm.",
        "The engine oil flowing."
      ],
      "answer": "Control of the vehicle."
    },
    {
      "question": "295. A helper should be used to help back your vehicle:",
      "choices": [
        "When you have a trailer.",
        "Whenever possible.",
        "When you need to back on a curved path."
      ],
      "answer": "Whenever possible."
    },
    {
      "question": "296. You should signal continuously while turning because:",
      "choices": [
        "You need both hands on the wheel to turn safely.",
        "It is illegal to turn off your signal before completing a turn.",
        "Most vehicles have self-canceling signals."
      ],
      "answer": "You need both hands on the wheel to turn safely."
    },
    {
      "question": "297. When approaching a traffic light that has been green for a long time, you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Accelerate so you get through the light.",
        "Start to slow down so you will be ready to stop.",
        "Continue at your current speed."
      ],
      "answer": "Start to slow down so you will be ready to stop."
    },
    {
      "question": "298. What three things add up to total stopping distance for your truck or bus?",
      "choices": [
        "Attention distance, reaction distance, slowing distance.",
        "Observation distance, reaction distance, braking distance.",
        "Perception distance, reaction distance, braking distance."
      ],
      "answer": "Perception distance, reaction distance, braking distance."
    },
    {
      "question": "299. If you cannot see well with your headlights when driving in an area with few streetlights on a clear night, you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Turn your interior lights on.",
        "Find another route that is better lit.",
        "Use your high beams when legal and keep your interior light off."
      ],
      "answer": "Use your high beams when legal and keep your interior light off."
    },
    {
      "question": "300. When driving at night, use your low beams when an oncoming vehicle is within:",
      "choices": [
        "300 feet.",
        "400 feet.",
        "500 feet."
      ],
      "answer": "500 feet."
    },
    {
      "question": "301. If your brakes get wet while driving on a rainy day, what can happen when you apply the brakes?",
      "choices": [
        "Hydroplaning.",
        "Excessive brake wear.",
        "Trailer Jackknife."
      ],
      "answer": "Trailer Jackknife."
    },
    {
      "question": "302. Which of these is a danger of crossing railroad tracks on dirt roads?",
      "choices": [
        "The ground underneath the tracks may not be stable.",
        "You could get hung up halfway across the tracks.",
        "Your tires could sink into the dirt and not cross the tracks."
      ],
      "answer": "You could get hung up halfway across the tracks."
    },
    {
      "question": "303. A key principle to remember about loading cargo is to keep the load:",
      "choices": [
        "To the front.",
        "To the rear.",
        "Balanced in the cargo area."
      ],
      "answer": "Balanced in the cargo area."
    },
    {
      "question": "304. Containerized loads:",
      "choices": [
        "Should come with their own tie-down devices.",
        "Are generally used for freight carried part way by rail or ship.",
        "Do not need to be inspected or secured by the driver."
      ],
      "answer": "Are generally used for freight carried part way by rail or ship."
    },
    {
      "question": "305. Can federal inspectors inspect your truck or bus?",
      "choices": [
        "Yes, but they cannot place it out of service.",
        "Yes, and they can place it out of service.",
        "No."
      ],
      "answer": "Yes, and they can place it out of service."
    },
    {
      "question": "306. Which of these is NOT required knowledge for drivers needing HAZMAT endorsement?",
      "choices": [
        "When to use placards.",
        "Which products can be loaded together.",
        "Basic chemistry."
      ],
      "answer": "Basic chemistry."
    },
    {
      "question": "307. When driving on grades, which of these is the best choice for a safe speed?",
      "choices": [
        "If you have a light load, you can go faster than those with a heavy load.",
        "Based on your vehicle and its cargo, select a speed that is safe within the posted limit.",
        "Follow the vehicle in front of you."
      ],
      "answer": "Based on your vehicle and its cargo, select a speed that is safe within the posted limit."
    },
    {
      "question": "308. Trucks and buses are subject to certain laws, restrictions, and regulations. Which of these statements is true?",
      "choices": [
        "County and city laws do not apply to trucks and buses engaged in interstate commerce.",
        "Federal regulations apply only to trucks and buses driven at least 50 miles on a trip.",
        "Laws and restrictions can vary from place to place."
      ],
      "answer": "Laws and restrictions can vary from place to place."
    },
    {
      "question": "309. When a doctor prescribes medication for you and you know you will be driving, you should:",
      "choices": [
        "Take the medication, but stop taking it if you notice it is affecting your driving.",
        "Take the medication, as well as other medication to keep you alert.",
        "Ask the doctor if the medication will affect your ability to drive."
      ],
      "answer": "Ask the doctor if the medication will affect your ability to drive."
    },
    {
      "question": "310. You should schedule your driving:",
      "choices": [
        "Between the hours of 4 am and 6 pm.",
        "Between the hours of 10 am and midnight.",
        "For the hours you are normally awake."
      ],
      "answer": "For the hours you are normally awake."
    },
    {
      "question": "311. Stab braking should not be used on vehicles with:",
      "choices": [
        "Air brakes.",
        "Spring brakes.",
        "Anti-lock brakes."
      ],
      "answer": "Anti-lock brakes."
    },
    {
      "question": "312. *If you do not have a CB radio, what is the first thing you should do at an accident scene?",
      "choices": [
        "Clear the area.",
        "Protect the accident scene.",
        "Flag down help."
      ],
      "answer": "Protect the accident scene."
    },
    {
      "question": "313. When driving in cold weather conditions, your tire tread should:",
      "choices": [
        "Have at least 4/32 inch tread on it.",
        "Have at least 2/32 inch tread on it.",
        "Provide enough traction to steer and push the vehicle through snow."
      ],
      "answer": "Provide enough traction to steer and push the vehicle through snow."
    },
    {
      "question": "314. When you are passing another vehicle, pedestrian, or bicyclist you should assume that they:",
      "choices": [
        "See you.",
        "Will move out of your lane of traffic.",
        "May move into your traffic lane."
      ],
      "answer": "May move into your traffic lane."
    },
    {
      "question": "315. Which of the following cannot be checked at the same time:",
      "choices": [
        "Headlights, brake lights, and clearance lights.",
        "Brake lights, flashers, and turn signals.",
        "Brake lights, turn signals, and clearance lights."
      ],
      "answer": "Brake lights, flashers, and turn signals."
    },
    {
      "question": "316. Cargo Inspections:",
      "choices": [
        "Should be performed as part of your pre-trip inspection again within the first 50 miles of your trip, then again after you have driven 3 hours or 150 miles.",
        "Should only be done at the start of your trip.",
        "Should be performed every 500 miles."
      ],
      "answer": "Should be performed as part of your pre-trip inspection again within the first 50 miles of your trip, then again after you have driven 3 hours or 150 miles."
    },
    {
      "question": "317. *Allowing for lawful exceptions, maximum legal height of any vehicle is:",
      "choices": [
        "14 feet.",
        "16 feet.",
        "12 feet."
      ],
      "answer": "14 feet."
    },
    {
      "question": "318. Allowing for permitted exceptions, the maximum length for a single vehicle is:",
      "choices": [
        "42 feet.",
        "44 feet.",
        "40 feet."
      ],
      "answer": "40 feet."
    },
    {
      "question": "319. If you drive for an employer who transports cargo intrastate (California) only, you may not drive for more:",
      "choices": [
        "12 hours between a work period.",
        "10 hours between a work period.",
        "14 hours between a work period."
      ],
      "answer": "12 hours between a work period."
    },
    {
      "question": "320. A driver's trip log, in duplicate if required, must be kept by each driver and co-driver while:",
      "choices": [
        "a. Driving on duty not driving, or resting in a sleeping berth.",
        "b. Operating the vehicle, regardless of duty status.",
        "c. Loading and unloading cargo."
      ],
      "answer": "a. Driving on duty not driving, or resting in a sleeping berth."
    },
    {
      "question": "321. Which of these problems, if discovered while checking your steering exhaust system, must be fixed before driving the vehicle?",
      "choices": [
        "a. Steering with a play of 45 degrees on a power system movement.",
        "b. Loose items in the cab.",
        "c. A dirty windshield."
      ],
      "answer": "a. Steering with a play of 45 degrees on a power system movement."
    },
    {
      "question": "322. Which of these is NOT a part of the pre-trip engine compartment inspection?",
      "choices": [
        "a. Accelerator cable.",
        "b. Engine oil level.",
        "c. Radiator coolant level."
      ],
      "answer": "a. Accelerator cable."
    },
    {
      "question": "323. It is raining, and you are stopped at a traffic signal. When the light turns green you apply power to the drive wheels, and they start to spin. You should:",
      "choices": [
        "a. Continue to accelerate to get out of the slippery spot.",
        "b. Quickly downshift to a lower gear.",
        "c. Take your foot off the accelerator."
      ],
      "answer": "c. Take your foot off the accelerator."
    },
    {
      "question": "324. It is best to signal at least",
      "choices": [
        "a. 3 seconds before changing lanes on the freeway.",
        "b. 5 seconds before changing lanes on the freeway.",
        "c. 10 seconds before changing lanes on the freeway."
      ],
      "answer": "b. 5 seconds before changing lanes on the freeway."
    },
    {
      "question": "325. You have a vehicle emergency, and you are parked on the side of an undivided highway. You should place your reflective triangles within",
      "choices": [
        "a. 50 feet of the front, 50 feet from the rear, 50 feet from the rear.",
        "b. 75 feet of the front, 25 feet from the rear, 75 feet from the rear.",
        "c. 100 feet of the front, 10 feet from the rear, 100 feet from the rear."
      ],
      "answer": "c. 100 feet of the front, 10 feet from the rear, 100 feet from the rear."
    },
    {
      "question": "326. For safety reasons, you should",
      "choices": [
        "a. Hold the reflective side of the triangle between yourself and the oncoming traffic.",
        "b. Place the triangles directly behind your vehicle.",
        "c. Use the triangles only during daylight hours."
      ],
      "answer": "a. Hold the reflective side of the triangle between yourself and the oncoming traffic."
    },
    {
      "question": "327. Which of these tips about speed management and braking is true?",
      "choices": [
        "a. You need the same stopping distance at all speeds.",
        "b. You need about four times stopping distance at 40 mph as at 20 mph.",
        "c. Braking distance is shorter on wet roads compared to dry roads."
      ],
      "answer": "b. You need about four times stopping distance at 40 mph as at 20 mph."
    },
    {
      "question": "328. You are passing a vehicle going 25 mph on a grade. Your passing speed should be at least and you must complete this pass in",
      "choices": [
        "a. 15 mph; a half mile.",
        "b. 35 mph; a quarter mile.",
        "c. 50 mph; an eighth of a mile."
      ],
      "answer": "b. 35 mph; a quarter mile."
    }
  ]
  
